Michael LaRocca

I am a physically active, science and tech nerd with 4 years of combined experience in the Nanotech and Biotech industries. Databases and SQL really peaked my interest in Full Stack Development, so I decided to fully immerse myself, joining a coding bootcamp in downtown San Diego. I've really taken to programming and want to become an expert Rails developer and Software Engineer. Check out my portfolio! https://michaellarocca90.github.io

San Diego, CA (949) 633-3647

michaellarocca90@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/laroccinthew orld/

www.github.com/michaellarocca90

EXPERIENCE

Biospyder, Carlsbad, CA

Database/Manufacturing Consultant

January 2017 - January 2018

- Trained employees in both Database and Manufacturing Operations.
- Scaled Database size by 100%.
- Initiated development of two flagship products.

Database Design/Oligonucleotide Manager

June 2015 - December 2016

- Designed a MySQL oligonucleotide inventory database for product development, record tracking, and custom requests.
 - Self-taught using Stanford Lagunita DB Series.
- Developed automated (Biomek Fx) oligonucleotide pooling and PCR plate manufacturing processes with QC checks.
- Delivered products for EPA grant deadlines.
- Completed development of three flagship products and numerous custom pools.

Herzan, Laguna Hills, CA

Product Manager

June 2014 - May 2015

- Reduced costs by 39.4% and increased margins by 22.3%.
- Managed a Hardware developer and C#/.NET Software Developer.
- Completed a hardware redesign, logo rebranding, and case design on a small budget.
- Performed Site Surveys for Electron Microscope and MRI installations.
- Wrote the User Manual.

SKILLS

Languages - Ruby, JavaScript/ES6, HTML5, CSS

Frameworks/Libraries - Rails, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap, Flexbox

Database - SQL, MySQL(2 years), Postgres

Testing/Tools - Rspec, Jest/Enzyme, Atom, Git

Dev Strategies - OOP, BDD, TDD, MVC, REST, Pair Programming

Software - MySQL Workbench, pgAdmin, MS Office

LANGUAGES

3 years of Spanish

AWARDS

Golden Eagle - 2012 Men's Track and Field recipient for academic and athletic success.

Captain - UCSB T&F 2012 Big-West Team Conference Champions

Captain - DHHS T&F 2007, 2008 2008 Team Championship All-County

Data Analyst and Tester

March 2014 - June 2014

- Analyzed vibration, acoustic, and electromagnetic data to determine product performance.
- Standardized templates for logging test data and reporting results to increase reporting efficiency and quality.

Self-Employed, San Diego, CA

Personal Trainer/Massage Therapist

May 2016 - Present

- Managed a 25+ client network based at Nakoa Fitness and Physical Therapy.
- Exercise programming and Manual Therapy techniques designed to target client goals including weight loss, pain management, and athletic performance.

EDUCATION

Learn Academy, San Diego — Full Stack Web Development

January 2018 - Expected May 2018

• Primarily developing apps with Rails on the back end as an API and React.js consuming the data on the front end.

Grow with Google Front-End Developer Scholarship

January 2018 - April 2018

• JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery

UCSB, Santa Barbara — B.S. Biochemistry and Molecular Biology

September 2008 - December 2012

• GPA: 3.3/4.0